ready one two three go
thank you for calling christian
technical support my name is candace
i'll be your resolution specialist for
today may i have your name please
hi candace this is sophie
and
i'm pretty sure i'm 30 minutes away from
getting fired
here's the problem my internet stopped
working and the clock is ticking
i was about to send my report this
morning i hit send and poof the
connection's gone i'm seeing an
exclamation point at the bottom of my
screen if that makes any sense to you
and it's saying
no internet it's nine and i need to send
my report before 10 so
a little help please
i apologize for this inconvenience
sophie i
i understand that this is a time
sensitive issue and
i'll do my best to fix your connection
before 10 hopefully so thank you thank
you that's exactly what i want to hear
this is an effective empathy statement
because it affirms the customer's goal
what does she want she wants her
internet to be fixed before 10 so she
can send her report and not get fired
it's my pleasure
um
so you said that you were unable to send
your report and the screen is showing no
internet
is it an intermittent connection where
it's cutting in and out or is it a
complete loss of connection a complete
loss it's not just low or
uh as you said intermittent intermittent
connection no i've been reloading it for
30 minutes straight now and there is
nothing whatsoever
intermittent connection and a complete
loss of connection are two different
problems that require two different
troubleshooting process
therefore it is important for candice to
know early on in this call which of the
two problems is sophie really
experiencing
so that is why she asked the question to
clarify
this right here is the first part of
probing
in order to find the solution you have
to define
the problem as specifically as you can
and in this case the specific problem is
a complete loss of connection
now that we've determined the problem we
need to find the solution and we do that
by
finding out the cause of the problem and
then addressing that problem here's the
complicated part
with most technical issues the cause of
the problem is never straightforward for
example in this scenario a complete loss
of connection i can think of five
different possible reasons why
sophie is experiencing this and it could
be a modern issue could be an outage in
the area it could be that sophie did not
pay her bill or forgot to pay her bill a
device issue or it could be an obscure
issue that only a technician could solve
so what does this mean for your ahd or
average handling time
this means that you have to investigate
five possible causes within a limited
average handling time
meaning you have to do it as short as
possible as fast as possible
how exactly do you do that based on
these five hypotheses how do you make
your troubleshooting process as fast and
efficient and short as possible
do you have an idea
you have five seconds to answer that
question
and the answer is you need to start with
a hypothesis that takes the least amount
of time to confirm as you can see in
this table it's the power outage and the
non-payment that take the least amount
of time to confirm so the sooner you can
rule these two out the faster and more
simplified it will be for you
so i made a call flow chart for you to
make sense of everything that candace is
telling the customer to do
here we start with a call you know thank
you for calling question technical
support
and then the customer says that she has
no internet connection and that is a
complete loss of connection right
so of course what you do is you pull up
her account obviously
now after pulling a per account you have
to start with the possible cause that's
that takes the least amount of time to
confirm in this case
is to check for outages all right and
then you have to ask yourself is there
an outage if the answer is yes all you
have to do is to advise the customer to
wait for the fix because
no amount of troubleshooting will solve
the issue but to just wait for the fix
from the company
what happens after that is the end of
the call that's it that's all you have
to do if it's an outage issue you cannot
do anything else
and so if it's not an outage issue what
you have to do is to check for unpaid
services and if she does have an unpaid
bill
you have to advise her to settle her
balance that's the only
solution for this problem and then you
end the call
but if it's not an unpaid bill then it
could be a modern issue or a device
issue
in which case you have to have the
customer check if a second device can
connect to the internet and check the
light indicators can a second device
connect if a second device can connect
and the lights on the modem are green
that means that it is a possible issue
of the first device because why else
could the other device connect so in
this case what you have to do
is to ensure that the internet physical
setup is correct the cable is undamaged
and properly plugged or that the
internet configuration setting is
correct so you basically have to pay
attention to your device setup but let's
say
that a second device also cannot connect
and there are
maybe red lights not green lights it
will be under no and so if that's the
case then it is a possible modern issue
in which case you have to ask the
customer to reset her modem did the
reset work
and the answer if the answer is no then
your last resort would be to dispatch a
technician because that's the last
resort so whatever happens here as you
can see
everything will lead to
you ending the call
but some problems as you can see are
less complicated and take less takes
take less time to solve and others like
modern issue and issue of the device
take longer to solve
so now we're going to continue with a
mock call is it an intermittent
connection where it's cutting in and out
or is it a complete loss of connection a
complete loss it's not just low or
uh as you said
internet intermittent connection no i've
been reloading it for 30 minutes
straight now and there is nothing
whatsoever
i see okay
okay so i'm going to start
troubleshooting now first thing i'm
going to do is to check for outages in
your area and for that i would need to
pull up your account may i may have your
account number it's uh
two and three
four five six
eight 879.
thank you
notice this pattern because this is
crucial
erc or explanation request
compliance so this is a very common
pattern when making a request to your
customer it's going to be like this
throughout the call erc erc a continuous
cycle of erc until there is a solution
but how exactly does erc look like as
you heard earlier the agent said so the
first thing i'm going to do now is to
pull up your account to check for
outages in your area
so that is the explanation
in this case the agent is telling the
customer her plan as to how
she would go about solving her problems
in the request part she said may you
know your account number after that we
know that the request is successful
because the customer gave her account
number so that's the first erc cycle of
this call now let's proceed and i want
you to notice the next one so i'm going
to start troubleshooting now first thing
i'm going to do is to check for outages
in your area and for that i would need
to pull up your account
may i have your account number it's
two and three
four five six uh
eight seven nine
thank you and your complete name and
best callback number sophie collins nine
six two one six four four five six six
awesome
and your four digit passcode
oh come on are you kidding me what is
that
where can i find that
uh do you remember the four digit
passcode you set up when you when you
ordered a service i don't i don't know
um
try one four two six okay one four two
six okay got it and lastly i just need
the address where your internet is
installed so i can check if there's an
ongoing outage in your area
1065 winterfell street
philadelphia pennsylvania 19093
thank you one moment please
while i'm checking for outages
by the way
candace at this moment is not just
checking for outages she's also checking
for
unpaid bills but she's not actually
gonna tell sophie that because what's
the point of saying
great sophie i see that your
loss of connection isn't isn't caused by
an unpaid bill what's the point of
saying that that would be
catastrophic for the rapport
um the likely response of sophie would
be like
of course i paid do you think i'm an
idiot you're wasting my time fix my
connection now why are you checking my
billing history of course i paid
so you don't want that to happen check
the billing history of your customer
secretly and only bring up that issue if
she really has an unpaid bill
all right there's no outage in your area
and there's no
open ticket submitted so far so
this brings us to the possible issue
with either your modem or your device
and for me to identify which i'm going
to ask you a series of questions to
diagnose the problem is that okay with
you okay
fair enough did you notice that that's
the second cycle of erc there's no
outage in your area and there's no
open ticket submitted so far so
this brings us to the possible issue
with either your modem or your device
and then it's followed by the request
and for me to identify which i'm going
to ask you a series of questions to
diagnose the problem is that okay with
you okay fair enough
the customer would have no problem
complying because she knows the purpose
of those questions this pattern is like
saying
this is the current status
here's what i need you to do and if you
do that i'm going to provide you with an
update or better yet a resolution later
so it's a it's a give and take
relationship you're making your customer
do things but at the same time you're
giving something in return because what
usually happens is that agents tend to
ask ask ask without giving anything in
return god only knows what the plan is
whether there's any progress the
customers don't don't have a clue they
feel lost and they feel impatient and no
wonder whereas with erc you're providing
your customers with mini updates along
the way so the customer would couldn't
help but think i'm going to follow what
this cos was that what this agent is
telling me to do because it sounds like
she knows what she's doing she keeps me
updated along the way she helps me
understand and she makes the process
less intimidating and it feels safe and
it feels good that is basically
to establish
trust with your customer this is really
all about trust if your customer doesn't
trust your ability or your willingness
to help her it's going to be hard for
you to make her do things and obtain
information from her and you might think
that well i'm the expert here why can't
she just bloody well listen to me
that is true but remember that your
customer has the eyes to see and and
the hands to move things around for you
so it is very important that she feels
that it it is a collaboration instead of
you trying to make her do things and not
explaining a thing there's no outage in
your area and there's no
open ticket submitted so far so
this brings us to the possible issue
with either your modem or your device
and for me to identify which i'm going
to ask you a series of questions to
diagnose the problem is that okay with
you okay fair enough okay thank you uh
so what device are you currently using
i'm using my desktop computer
are you using a wired connection or a
wireless connection yes the one
plugged in behind the cpu
so
it is a wired connection from your cpu
to your modem right yes it's a wired
connection
okay
are you in the same room as your modem
where your internet is set up
i'm sorry honey about i don't know what
a modem is but
yes i think i'm in the same room where
your technician set up my internet so
okay great um so your modem is the flat
rectangular box
it has
it has two upright antennas it's black
and it has a white question logo on top
of it do you see it somewhere i see it
okay uh i also see power internet
w-l-a-m
l-a-n another thing um am i looking at
the right thing yeah yes yes you are
that's your modem um could you tell me
the colors of the indicator lights from
each of those
i see flashing lights and there's a lot
of red here that's not a good sign is it
no no it's not a good sign
red is a sign that something is
malfunctioning and we have to identify
which so could you tell me which parts
are in red is it the internet is it the
land
i see red on internet on wlan and lan
okay
this sounds like a modem issue to me
because of the red lights and i'm
assuming that your other devices are
also not working right could you could
you please connect another device maybe
try playing a video on youtube or browse
yeah i wouldn't get my hopes up honey
but let me see one second let me play
some youtube cat videos
okay
nope
nope not working same issue okay
okay
then we're gonna do a modern reset since
there's no outage in your area and yet
your modem is flashing red
so okay that makes sense
what do you want me to do
okay so at the back of your modem do you
see a black cable it's um it's thin and
it's connected to a port that says power
hold on
um
yes i see it
okay great now please unplug that for at
least 30 seconds all right
oh
this is
a little hard to unplug
okay
okay it's unplugged all right
so now all lights from your modem should
be off yep they're turned off all right
okay so i just need to wait 30 seconds
right yes and after 30 seconds plug it
back in okay
okay it's just weird nobody was touching
it this morning it just stopped working
yes this could happen sometimes
due to occasional glitches but but
this shouldn't happen very often um
is this your first time experiencing
this since you signed up with us last
march
yeah
yeah this is my first time for sure okay
and i hope to god this works because
worst case scenario i'd have to run to
my starbucks and buy a coffee just to
connect and
i'm on a spending detox and i can spend
so much money so
this better work
yeah i i understand um
i spend an insane amount of money in
starbucks too so we understand but we're
gonna we're gonna find out soon in a few
seconds and hopefully this will solve it
if not we're gonna try we're gonna we're
gonna do something else that's for sure
the part for small talk you're waiting
for the modem to reboot you have nothing
else to do what else are you gonna do
small talk
and
the good thing about the small talk in
this conversation is that
it's related to the issue at hand so
it's not that
hard to small talk
now a small thought is going to be a
topic for another video but know that
there are going to be parts
in the troubleshooting process where
you're going to you're going to wait for
something to reboot and you have to talk
to your customer
to avoid awkward silences and this is
one of those we understand but we're
gonna we're gonna find out soon in a few
seconds and hopefully this will solve it
if not we're gonna try we're gonna we're
gonna do something else that's for sure
okay
uh so i am now plugging it back in
here it goes
voila it's plugged great okay
now we just need to wait for one more
minute for it to come for it to
completely restart
okay
and after that all the lights should
turn green others will blink that's
normal but there should be no more red
lights all right um
do you mind staying on the line until i
can confirm that it's working okay i
don't want to call second time and
explain again in case it doesn't
of course i also need to confirm that
it's resolved before i could end the
call so take your time
thank you
um
do you think i can do this on my own the
next time my internet stops working
unplug then re-plug the cable i know i
should have thought about this before
but i don't want to tinker with
something i'm not too sure of so
that's a great idea yes
in fact um your modem is a good place to
start when you're having connection
issues
think of it like a
like a first aid if you will
for connection problems and and that
will save you time too because it does
solve most connection problems
exactly but i didn't know that i started
calling you guys this morning it was
around
i remember it was around 8 am sharp
and i was number 98 on the queue and my
call got picked up only around 9. i mean
that's a long wait oh yeah yes it is and
and i apologize for that
we're usually not this busy at this time
of year but
last week
we had this major system upgrade and
some services were disrupted and now
lots of our customers are calling but
next week
everything should go back to normal huh
just my luck huh that i got this problem
right when you're having a high call
volume
yeah um it looks like it that seems to
be the case yes because
your issue doesn't seem to be related to
our system upgrade it just so happened
that you're calling in the middle of an
upgrade so
i'm so sorry about that oh well just my
luck
nothing can be done about it
all right um
i think it's already two minutes
okay can you test your internet and see
if you're connected maybe try sending
your report okay uh well um let me check
my phone first because i have it closer
to me
okay
it looks like
my youtube is now working on my phone
okay i already browsed okay is that okay
here it is
okay yeah it's working now the cat
videos are playing
okay
okay wonderful wonderful now what about
your desktop now let me check the other
one let me check my desktop
let me see
hold on
okay okay
oh hold on hold on something is wrong
i'm trying to send my report right now
for my desktop and uh it's still not
working i'm still seeing the no internet
prompt oh
why
okay
so your phone is working but not your
desktop right
yes correct
could you pl could you please check
again the light indicators on your modem
are there any red lights still
no they're all green some of them are
blinking but they're all green okay
could the blinking parts be the problem
no a blinking green light is normal we
only need to watch out for the red
okay so
there's a great chance that the issue
isn't with your modem anymore because a
the red lights are
are now green and your phone
is already connected but not your
desktop so
yeah it's weird that's certainly weird
problem is i need to send my report via
desktop so i really need this fixed of
course of course and we're going to do
that now could you do me a favor and
check if the cable connected to your cpu
is the exact cable connected to your
modem
of course it is look there's only one
cable so it can't be the problem can it
you're right you're right it's unlikely
but before we proceed to the more
complicated steps it's advisable that we
confirm the basic setup first
this will be quick it'll be finished
before you know it okay
fine
thank you in this part
sophie instead of complying to candace's
request
lodged an objection
and that's normal even if you you use
the erc framework there's gonna be a
point in the troubleshooting process
where the customer is getting impatient
and if the customer just doesn't see the
point of doing what you want her to do
then she's going to lodge an objection
in this case the customer didn't see the
point of checking the cable because as
she said there's only one cable what's
the point of checking if it's the exact
cable connected from the cpu to the
modem as the agent you could overcome
your customers objection by
understanding where they're coming from
and
acknowledging the validity of their
reasoning
in this case candice said
you're right you're right it's unlikely
so that's a very short sentence but it's
already an acknowledgement that yes i do
see the point of your reasoning
and but then candace proceeded to say
but before we proceed to the more
complicated steps it's advisable that we
confirm the basic setup first candice
proceeded to emphasize the the
importance of following the basic setup
first before proceeding to the mo to the
more complicated steps and she even
added this will be quick it'll be
finished before you know it okay
fine you know she's just coming up with
the reasons for sophie to follow her
instructions and
one one of the ways to do that is to
emphasize that it's going to be fast and
that's true by the way it's it's just a
fast checking of the setup add up first
this will be quick it'll be finished
before you know it okay
fine
thank you so is the cable properly
plugged in not loosely plugged or frayed
or twisted in any way could you check
for me
well um
i'm sure it's fine but
give it one second thank you
okay
okay it looks okay to me but
you know what what is it you will not
believe what i'm seeing right now the
cable the cable is
horribly horribly twisted what is going
on here
i think i discovered a problem see
at the back of the
cpu the cable is barely plugged and the
wire
the wire is so twisted what is going on
here
really well um
if if that's the case i wouldn't wonder
if that's the very reason why it isn't
working could you could you try plugging
it in properly
hold on i'm re-plugging it now okay i
swear it was working just last night i
don't know what happened here oh
oh i think
my grandson happened here dylan
dylan honey
what have you been playing this
have you been playing with crystal here
this morning
it's not my sister did you play with my
computer
no do not play here okay
hold on hold on sorry
sorry let me try to
okay it's plugged i'm sorry i i didn't
think they'd actually play here but it
looks like they did no problem no
problem let's just be thankful that they
were not hurt and that's a good thing
that you found out so you could keep
them safe next time
that could be dangerous oh i need to
lock this room from now on jesus christ
these kids
anyway um it looks like it's working now
i don't see the exclamation point
anymore uh hold on let me try to send my
report okay of course go ahead
so let me access my drafts and
attach more files
this
and
and this
finally thank you so much candice thank
you so much oh it's my pleasure sophie
oh you're a lifesaver that's for sure
oh
well i'm i'm very glad that i helped you
not to spend money on starbucks today so
oh don't i agree
so would there be anything else that i
can help you with today
nope but thank you so much you're
getting a five star
thank you and thank you so much for
being my troubleshooting partner today
just a quick recap you called in today
because your phone and desktop couldn't
connect to the internet first we reset
your modem and then we ensure that the
cable from your cpu to your modem was
properly connected and now both are
connected all right and this right here
is the recap based on my research with
troubleshooting calls you have to always
do the recap no matter what personally i
think that it's unnecessary
because did you hear
what candice just said she basically
just reviewed
everything that happened in the
troubleshooting process and confirm it
with sophie
for me recap is something you do when
there's something that you don't want
the customer to forget for example she
wants to return an item
and
you want her to remember that hey you
need to
put them in the original packaging and
you need to remember that there are
things that are non-returnable but in
this case it's just a troubleshooting
issue and the customer basically
knows what happened
in the call because she just had it with
you
so for me it doesn't really make sense
that there would be a recap in a
troubleshooting call but i guess if i
have to guess
maybe
the purpose for a recap is for qas to
know exactly what happened in that call
without listening to the whole whole
call other than that it feels like you
know in a telenovela you're telling the
customer
or you know previously because if i'm
the customer i would hear an agent doing
a recap i would just be thinking in my
head
yeah i i know exactly what we did in
this call
because i i just talked to you
so anyway but know that recap is always
going to be a part of a troubleshooting
call for whatever reason just know that
quick recap you called in today because
your phone and desktop couldn't connect
to the internet first we reset your
modem and then we ensure that the cable
from your cpu to your modem was properly
connected and now both are connected yep
now i'm gonna have a word with my
grandkids
you have yourself a great day candace
bye
you too sophie thank you for calling
christian technical support bye because
this is such a heavy lesson i am doing a
summary
for all the things that you need to
remember from this video and i want you
to screenshot these summaries because
they're very important for you
first is how to probe effectively
the erc the explanation request
compliance
so call flow wise these are the steps
for a troubleshooting call
and lastly some of you might say that
this is a pretty tame customer and she's
not really irate that's true and this is
also a very basic problem that's true i
did this on purpose because
i want to focus on the foundational
principle of handling a troubleshooting
call and making the problem
complicated
would just make it
just very complicated for you to
understand so this is already a very
complicated lesson i don't want it i
want to complicate things so yeah i just
did it i just created a very simple
problem
demonstrating the
the
principles of handling this type of call
and so that's it